paradoxplaza.com 2015-12-21

# Privacy Policy - Paradox Interactive - Paradox Interactive

**Paradoxplaza.com**

**PRIVACY AND COOKIES POLICY**

Paradox Interactive AB, and its subsidiaries and affiliates (“Paradox Interactive,” “we” or “us”) respect your privacy and are committed to complying fully with Swedish laws and regulations regarding online privacy protection, and any information you provide to Paradox Interactive via [www.paradoxplaza.com](http://www.paradoxplaza.com/) and its subsidiary sites (collectively, the “Site”), including via the use of a Paradox account or Forum account (each, an “Account”), or via the use of any of our interactive software games (the “Game” or “Games”), will be treated in accordance with those laws and regulations and as set forth herein this privacy and cookies policy (the “Privacy and Cookies Policy”). Visitors to the Site from outside Sweden are advised that this Privacy and Cookies Policy is intended to meet the laws and requirements of Sweden, which may not be the same as the laws and regulations of your home country.

We are providing you with this Privacy and Cookies Policy in order to inform you of our policies with respect to information collected from visitors to the Site or to any Game. Your use of the Site or Game, or your creation of an Account, constitutes your acceptance of this Privacy and Cookies Policy and your consent to the practices it describes. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH THIS PRIVACY AND COOKIES POLICY, PLEASE DO NOT USE THE SITE, GAME OR ACCOUNT.

**1\. Automatic Collection of Anonymous Information**  
Paradox Interactive may collect information including internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks. We collect this information in the form of log files so that we can analyze trends, administer the Site or Game, track users’ movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. Log files are not linked to Personally Identifiable Information (defined below). Additionally, we may use a tracking utility that uses log files to analyze user movement.

**2\. Personally Identifiable Information**

Personally identifiable information is any information that concerns you individually and would permit someone to contact you, for example, your name, address, country of residence, telephone number, e-mail address, any credit card information you submit to the Site, or any information you submit to the Site, Game or Account that identifies you individually (“Personally Identifiable Information”).

We will not collect any Personally Identifiable Information about you unless you provide it. Therefore, if you do not want Paradox Interactive to obtain any Personally Identifiable Information about you, do not submit it.

You can visit and browse the Site without revealing Personally Identifiable Information about yourself. You may also choose to disclose Personally Identifiable Information about yourself, which may be maintained as described below. We may collect Personally Identifiable Information about you through registration forms, which may require you to provide, without limitation, your name, e-mail address, postal address, country of residence, telephone number, birth date, areas of interest, product usage, and/or a unique individual password. Such forms may be required to purchase products from Paradox Interactive, to enter a promotion, to become a registered user, or to request information about Paradox Interactive and its products and services through another site.

Should you choose to communicate with Paradox Interactive through e-mail, via the Site, by telephone, in writing, or through other means, we may collect the information in these communications, and such information may be Personally Identifiable Information.

We may also collect Personally Identifiable Information about you when you make a purchase through the Site or when you create an Account to make such purchase. If you would like to correct or delete any Personally Identifiable Information, please contact us at [www.paradoxplaza.com/support](http://www.paradoxplaza.com/support) or support@paradoxplaza.com.

**3\. “Cookies”**

The Paradox Interactive servers, or the servers of companies that are used to operate the Site, may place a “cookie” on your computer in order to allow you to use the Site and to personalize your experience. A cookie can be stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. Cookies allow us to recognize your computer while you are on the Site and help customize your online experience and make it more convenient for you. Cookies are also useful in allowing more efficient log-in for users, tracking transaction histories and preserving information between sessions. The information collected from cookies may also be used to improve the functionality of the Site and to measure traffic patterns.

There are two main kinds of cookies: session cookies and persistent cookies. Session cookies are deleted from your computer when you close your browser, whereas persistent cookies remain stored on your computer until deleted, or until they reach their expiry date.  You are entitled to choose whether or not you would like to use cookies. If you do not consent to the use of cookies, please be sure to block or disable them using your browser settings as described below or the opt-out link provided to you on your first visit to the Site.

Paradox Interactive uses the following cookies on the Site, for the following purposes:

a) Strictly Necessary Cookies: These cookies are necessary for the Site to function. They are usually set in response to actions made by you which amount to a request for services, such as logging in or filling in forms. You can set your browser to block or alert you about these cookies, but some parts of the Site might then not work. These cookies do not store any personally identifiable information;

b) Performance Cookies: These cookies allow us to count visits and traffic sources in order to measure and improve the performance of the Site. These cookies help us to know which pages are the most and least popular and how visitors move around the Site. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous. If you do not allow these cookies, we will not know when you have visited our Site, and will not be able to monitor its performance;

c) Functionality Cookies: These cookies enable the Site to provide enhanced functionality and personalization. They may be set by us or by third party providers whose services have been added to the Site. If you do not allow these cookies, some or all of these services may not function properly;

d) Targeting Cookies: Advertisers and/or other content providers that may appear on our Site may also use cookies that are not sent by us. Such advertisements or content may use cookies to help track and target the interests of users of the Site in order to present customized and personalized advertisements or other messages that the user might find interesting. These cookies do not store any personally identifiable information, but are based on uniquely identifying your browser and Internet device. Such cookies may even impact your experience of other websites you may visit subsequently. If you do not allow these cookies, you will experience less targeted advertising. Paradox Interactive is not responsible for any such cookies.

Please note that most web browser applications (such as Microsoft Internet Explorer, Mozilla Firefox and Google Chrome) have features that can notify you when you receive a cookie or prevent cookies from being sent. In Internet Explorer, you can refuse all cookies by clicking “Tools”, “Internet Options”, “Privacy”, and selecting “Block all cookies” using the sliding selector. In Firefox, you can adjust your cookies by clicking “Tools”, “Options” and “Privacy”. In Google Chrome, you can also adjust your cookies by clicking on “Settings”, “Show advanced settings”, “Content settings” and on the “Privacy” section.

If you disable cookies, however, you may not be able to use certain personalized functions of the Site.

**4\. Information Use and Storage Period**

Paradox Interactive may use Personally Identifiable Information collected through the Site, Game or Account to, among other things, respond to inquiries or comments, to verify the identity of users, to maintain or administer user accounts, to maintain the security and integrity of the Site and its data, to provide support to users, to process transactions, to communicate with users regarding transactions made via the Site, to improve and personalize the Site for user preferences, to provide users with product or service updates, promotional notices, and to offer services and products of interest to users.

Paradox Interactive uses the anonymous information collected automatically by our servers primarily to help us administer and improve our Site and Game. We may also use aggregated anonymous information to provide information about our Site to advertisers, potential business partners and other unaffiliated entities. Again, this information is not personally identifiable.

Paradox Interactive will not store Personally Identifiable Information longer than necessary for the purpose of the collection. Due to tax regulations however, Paradox Interactive usually stores any collected information (Personally Identifiable Information and anonymous information) for a period of five (5) years.

**5\. Disclosure of Information**

We may use unaffiliated companies to help us maintain and operate the Site or for other reasons related to the operation of our business, and those companies may receive your Personally Identifiable Information for that purpose. We may also disclose Personally Identifiable Information about you in connection with legal requirements, such as in response to an authorized subpoena, governmental request or investigation, or as otherwise permitted by law. Finally, we may sell or buy corporate assets, and in such transactions user information may be one of the transferred business assets. If Paradox Interactive or certain of its assets are acquired, user information may be transferred. Paradox Interactive does not sell Personally Identifiable Information to third parties.

**6\. Security**

Paradox Interactive maintains physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to help guard Personally Identifiable Information. If transactions are offered on the Site, transaction information is transmitted to and from the Site in encrypted form using industry-standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) connections to help protect such information from interception. Paradox Interactive restricts authorized access to your personal information to those persons who have a legitimate purpose to know that information to provide products or services to you and those persons you have authorized to have access to such information. Paradox Interactive also has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control (e.g., verification of Site user’s identity through username and password). Please be aware, however, that any e-mail or other transmission you send through the Internet cannot be completely protected against unauthorized interception, and it is your sole responsibility to protect the secrecy of your password.

**7\. Children's Privacy**

You must be at least 13 years of age to create any Account on the Site, and if you are between 13 and 18 years of age, you must get your parents’ or legal guardians’ consent prior to creating such Account. Paradox Interactive does not knowingly collect information from children under 13. If you are a parent or guardian of a child under 13 whom you believe has created an account on the Site, you may contact us at www.paradoxplaza.com/support or [support@paradoxplaza.com](mailto:support@paradoxplaza.com) and we will remove that account. You can also find our full contact details at <https://www.paradoxplaza.com/about-us/contact>.

**8\. External Links**

This Privacy and Cookies Policy does not extend to other sites on the Internet that are owned and operated by third party vendors and other third parties to which we may link (“External Sites”). Please be aware that Paradox Interactive is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of External Sites. External Sites may use cookies. Paradox Interactive encourages you to read the privacy policies provided by External Sites before you provide Personally Identifiable Information to them.

**9\. Severance**

If any of this Privacy and Cookies Policy is determined to be illegal, invalid or otherwise unenforceable by reason of the laws of any state or country in which this Privacy and Cookies Policy is intended to be effective, then to the extent and within the jurisdiction in which that term is illegal, invalid or unenforceable, it shall be severed and deleted from this Privacy and Cookies Policy and the remaining terms of the Privacy and Cookies Policy shall survive, remain in full force and effect, and continue to be binding and enforceable.

**10\. Governing Law/Jurisdiction**

This Privacy and Cookies Policy is governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of Sweden. You agree to submit to the personal jurisdiction of the courts of Stockholm, Sweden for any cause of action arising out of or relating to this Privacy and Cookies Policy, and hereby waive any right to participate in any type of law suit brought and/or maintained as a class action or similar in nature to a class action, to the extent permissible by applicable law.

**11\. Modifications of this Privacy and Cookies Policy**

Paradox Interactive shall have the right, at its sole discretion, to modify, add or remove any terms or conditions of this Privacy and Cookies Policy without notice or liability to you. Any changes to the Privacy and Cookies Policy shall be effective immediately following the posting of any such changes on the Site. Please review this Privacy and Cookies Policy regularly to ensure you are aware of any changes made by Paradox Interactive. Your continued use of the Site after changes are posted means you agree to be legally bound by this Privacy and Cookies Policy as updated and amended, to the extent permissible by applicable law.

**12\. Contacting Us**

If you have questions about this Privacy and Cookies Policy, the information practices of Paradox Interactive or your dealings with Paradox Interactive, please contact us at [www.paradoxplaza.com/support](http://www.paradoxplaza.com/support).

Paradox Interactive AB

_Date last modified: March 12, 2015_
